A Guide to the Papers of Collins Denny, 1881-1962 and n. d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Collins Denny 1881-1964 and n. d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
2672-k, -l
This collection consists of 23 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains photographs and copies of Denny family members and friends together with explanations of each supplied by Elizabeth Chapman (Denny) Vann. Also in the papers are memorabilia, clippings and obituaries for family members, a list of the religious denominations of U. Va. students kept in 1889 by Collins Denny, and Denny's printed letter of refusal to leave to leave the Methodist Episcopal Church, South and join the United Methodist Episcopal Church.
Contents List
- Photograph and negative of Log Cabin Parsonage, Fairfax, Virginia ca. 1881
  Home of Bishop Collins Denny
- 2 Photographs and negative of Bishop A. W. Wilson 1888 March 24
- 2 Photographs and negative of Hon. James W. Denny of Baltimore, Maryland, taken during the session of the 58th Congress 1905
- Photograph and negative of sons of Professors at Vanderbilt University, Collins Denny, Jr. at right end ca. 1910
- Photograph and negative of the Denny family n. d.
- Photograph and negative of William R. Denny of Winchester, Virginia n. d.
- Photograph and negative of Samuel L. Clemens n. d.
- Photocopies of orders, an oath, a pass, a certificate of exemption and 2 articles re: Col. William R. Denny ca. 1859- ca. 1865
- Photocopy of a football game program, includes the name C. Denny, listed as captain of the Princeton team 1875 Nov. 13
- Register of name skept by Collins Denny while at the University of Virginia Parsonage, includes a list of Bible Class members at the University 1889-1891
- Transcripts of school reports preserved by Mrs. Collins Denny re: Elizabeth Denny's progress at West Side School, "Little Vanderbilt," together with transcripts of Elizabeth Denny's compositions and a diary. ca. 1893- ca. 1895
- 29 Newspaper clippings (photocopies), mainly obituaries of Col. William Denny 1904 Dec. 5-1905 April 27
- Printed letter, Bishop Collins Denny to the Uniting Conference of the Methodist Church re: unification. 1939 May 19
- Newspaper clipping and TMs (photocopies) re: Bishop Denny and football at Princeton [ ca. 1940?]
- Letter (photocopy), Collins to Elizabeth re: Col. Denny's Civil War experiences. 1962 Oct. 7
- 2 Newsclippings (photocopies), editorial re: Collins Denny, Jr.'s death, from the Richmond News Leader, and an obituary from The Birmingham News. 1964 Jan. 15 and 18
- Business card of Collins Denny. n. d.
- Program of Sunday Services at the University of Virginia. Mar 7-28
- Biographical sketch of the Hon. James William Denny, member of Congress from Maryland n. d., TMs.
- Biographical sketch of Bishop Alpheus Wilson of Baltimore, Maryland. n. d., TMs.
- Historical sketch of the Log Cabin Parsonage at Fairfax Court House, Virginia, by Elizabeth C. Denny Vann. n. d., TMsS.
- Photograph and negative of the parsonage of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South in Lewisburg, West Virginia, home of the Rev. and Mrs. Collins Denny and their daughters Margaret and Elizabeth. 1884-1886
- Photograph and negative of Allen A. Chapman of Baltimore, Maryland, Mrs. Collins Denny's father. n. d.